Finding Aid for Society of Minority Engineering Students (University of Michigan) records, 1979-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Society of Minority Engineering Students (University of Michigan) records 1979-1996
Society of Minority Engineering Students (University of Michigan).
1 linear foot
9624 Bimu 2
University of Michigan student organization established to aid in recruitment, retention, and placement of minority engineering students. Records include minutes, organizational information, and activities material and publications.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Records are received periodically from the unit.(Donor no. 7940 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Society of Minority Engineering Students (SMES) was founded in 1974. The Minority Engineering Program (MEPO) organized SMES in an attempt to increase minority involvement in the College of Engineering.
SMES assists minority students as they develop personally, academically, and professionally. The Society of Minority Engineering Students stresses the importance of a well-rounded social life, sponsoring picnics, an open house for parents and students, and the Senior dinner which honors the graduating members of SMES. Academically, SMES sponsors study nights allowing fellow students to aid and support each other as well as offering free tutorial services. Professionally, SMES offers workshops on interviewing, resume writing, and industrial tours.
The society of Minority Engineers record group is organized into two series Records and Publications. The Records series includes minutes, organizational information, activities material and a brief account of Gardner Leverett's tenure as SMES president, 1990/91.
The Publications series includes Directories and resumé books, programs and a newsletter. The SMES Resumé Book contains the resumés of SMES members. These can be sent directly to personnel departments of major corporations throughout the nation upon request. There is an almost complete run (1979-1993) of this publication in the printed materials subgroup.
The annual SMES Industrial Banquet brings together job candidates and representatives from major corporations in a relaxed, yet professional environment allowing the recruits and the recruiters more personal contact. There is a nearly complete run of the programs for this dinner from 1979 to 1996.
Subjects:
Society of Minority Engineering Students (University of Michigan); Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs; Resume book.; Resume directory.; SMES news.
Genre Terms:
Brochures.; Directories.; Newsletters.; Programs.
- Records
  - Minutes, 1898-1994 (Box 1)
  - Organization (Box 1)
  - Activities (Box 1)
  - Gardner Leverett, Personal History as President (Box 1)
- Publications
  - Unit Publications
    - Brochures, 1985-1995 (Box 1-P)
    - Directories
      - Directory of Underrepresented Student Societies in the College of Engineering and Related Sciences, 1998-99 Academic Year (Box 1-P)
      - Resumés 79, 1979 (Box 1-P)
      - Resumés, 1981 (Box 1-P)
      - Resumé Directory, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Resumé Book, 1985-1992/1993, 9 folders (Box 1-P)
    - Newsletters
      - SMES News, 1990 (Box 1-P)
    - Programs
      - Annual Industrial Awards Banquet, 1979-1996, 3 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Professional Development Conference, 1986 (Box 1-P)
      - How We've Grown: In Celebration of 25 years of excellence. 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1998 (Box 1-P)